Imagine yourself in the finance department at Parch &amp; Posey.
تخيّلوا أنفسكم في قسم الشؤون المالية في Parch وPosey.
You want to look up the most recent orders,
تريدون البحث عن الطلبات الأحدث،
so that you can confirm that invoices have been sent to those customers.
بحيث تتمكنون من التأكد من إرسال الفواتير إلى هؤلاء العملاء.
The Order By clause will help you accomplish this,
ستساعدكم عبارة Order By على إتمام هذا،
by allowing you to sort the orders by date.
عن طريق السماح لكم بفرز الطلبات حسب التاريخ.
Let's first take a look at how the data is ordered by default.
لنلقِ نظرة أولاً على كيفية ترتيب البيانات افتراضيًا.
You'll notice that this table appears to be sorted by Account ID by default.
ستلاحظون أن هذا الجدول يظهر وكأنه تم فرزه حسب مُعرّف الحساب افتراضيًا.
It starts at 1001, and goes up from there.
يبدأ من 1001، ويبدأ في الازدياد من هناك.
Let's add an Order By clause to
لنضف عبارة Order By لإعادة
reorder the results based on the date the order was placed,
ترتيب النتائج استنادًا إلى التاريخ الذي تم فيه الطلب،
which you can see in the occurred_at column.
والذي يمكنكم رؤيته في عمود تم الحدوث في.
Notice that the order by clause goes between the From and Limit clauses.
لاحظوا أن عبارة order by تكون بين فقرة من وفقرة الحد.
You have to write the clauses in this order,
يتعين عليكم كتابة العبارات بهذا الترتيب،
or the query will not run.
وإلا فلن يعمل الاستعلام.
By default, order by goes from a to z,
يبدأ الترتيب افتراضيًا حسب من أ إلى ي،
lowest to highest, or earliest to latest,
أو من الأدنى إلى الأعلى، أو من الأقدم إلى الأحدث،
if working with dates.
في حالة التعامل مع التواريخ.
This is referred to as ascending order.
يُشار إلى هذا بالترتيب التصاعدي.
You'll notice that that's what's happening here.
ستلاحظون أن هذا ما سيحدث هنا.
If you want to order the other way,
إذا كنتم تريدون الترتيب بطريقة أخرى،
you can add DESC,
يمكنكم إضافة DESC،
short for descending, to the end of the Order By clause.
وهو اختصار لكلمة تنازلي، إلى نهاية عبارة Order By.
This will get us to the data set that we're after,
سيوصلنا هذا إلى مجموعة البيانات التالية لدينا،
which shows the 10 most recent orders,
والتي تعرض الترتيبات العشرة الأخيرة،
with the most recent at the top.
مع جعل الأحدث في الأعلى.